[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[The Spring of the Sword]
[Episode 7]
So get ready.
You can inform Mrs. Xie tomorrow.
He's already gone.
You don't need to keep acting.
Wow, that was fast.
You change your attitude.
You asked me
that I would play along with you tonight.
But now that you don't need me anymore, you're pushing me aside.
Although it's okay.
Our performance is over.
Now it's our turn to be spectators.
My concubine,
How cruel you are!
I've done so many dirty things for you.
So what now?
After using me, you want to get rid of me
and send me to my death?
Move aside!
We still haven't settled the score for what happened last time!
Nana Rong,
What happened?
Why are you so upset?
When you handed over the management of the estate,
You made sure not to leave anything that could implicate you,
But you kept the promissory notes.
that I processed.
It's perfectly clear.
If something goes wrong, you want to make me your scapegoat!
Nana Rong,
You're getting more and more confused.
You can't even tell the difference between the lady and the maid anymore.
Are you expecting
that I, your lady,
How can you help me do the work, when you're the maid?
But I didn't pocket the money we got.
Don't worry.
Qingyuan will not be able to control the tenant peasant riots.
When Mrs. Xie demands answers,
She will barely be able to save herself.
He won't have time to take care of you.
Besides,
The head of the family will return soon.
We just need to keep a low profile for a few days.
I am the one who manages this house.
As long as you're on my side,
You have nothing to fear.
Desperation made me lose my mind and disrespect him...
You can leave.
We cannot leave alive
to that insolent maid.
Accounts.
Yes, Mrs. May.
When they hand over Nanny Rong
to the authorities and have her hanged,
There will be no one left who can testify.
By then,
The concubine Mei will be able to escape all responsibility
And you will be able to discover the truth.
Get out! Move aside!
Don't worry.
Qingyuan will not be able to control the tenant peasant riots.
When Mrs. Xie demands answers,
She will barely be able to save herself.
He won't have time to take care of you.
So get ready.
You can inform Mrs. Xie tomorrow.
No.
If I want to stay alive,
I'll have to go to Mrs. Xie.
Mrs. Xie has arrived!
Make way!
The manager has arrived.
It's Mrs. Xie.
That's how it is.
Give us back our money! Give us back our money!
- Grandma. - They have to give us an explanation today!
They have to give us an explanation today!
Give us back our money! Give us back our money!
Greetings, Grandma.
What brings her here?
You've only been in charge of the ranch for a few days.
And you've already caused such a serious problem.
that these people ended up surrounding her.
I don't even know anymore.
if you still respect
to your grandmother.
Grandmother,
I've been a bad granddaughter
and I have disturbed their peace.
I was just thinking
in covering the shortfall in the accounts.
I planned to resolve this matter
before informing him,
but I didn't expect
that he come in person.
Mrs. Xie, please calm down.
La Srta. Qingyuan
He returned home just a few months ago.
How could he have caused such a serious problem?
Thank you!
Stop it!
Get out of the way!
How dare you arrest me? Don't you know who I am?
Thank you!
Sra. Xie.
What have you come for?
Why are you shouting so much?
What kind of manners are those?
Sra. Xie,
I am guilty.
I beg you
that allows me to die in the Xie mansion.
I did not surrender to the authorities.
What nonsense!
What are you saying?
I knew nothing about usurious loans
that were granted on the estate.
But Miss Qingyuan
He wants to frame me
and make me take all the blame.
You...
Qingyuan,
it's true?
Grandmother,
after taking charge of the estate,
I found it in the warehouse
several promissory notes processed by Nana Rong.
That's why I scattered it on purpose
Sapan wood powder in the warehouse
and I waited for
someone came to steal the evidence.
Just as I expected,
The promissory notes disappeared last night.
Therefore,
It had to be Nana Rong who took them away.
What I didn't expect was
that he came here today to proclaim his innocence.
Grandmother,
Simply pour in alum water
on the soles of their shoes.
The sapán powder will turn red
and then
The whole truth will come to light.
Someone come!
Yeah.
A man should not touch a woman!
How indecent!
Damn servants!
Let me go!
Give me back the shoe.
Put it there!
No...
Look at it closely.
What do you have to say now?
Confess the whole truth!
I will speak.
I'll tell you everything.
La Srta. Qingyuan
It has nothing to do with this.
It was Mrs. Mei!
It was all Mrs. Mei's doing!
She ordered me to secretly grant usurious loans.
But things went wrong.
I failed to recover
none of the borrowed money.
That left a shortfall in the treasury's accounts.
Then, I don't know how,
The tenants found out.
They were afraid they wouldn't receive their payments.
That's why they gathered to protest.
When Mrs. Mei saw that everything had become complicated,
He passed on the problem
a la Srta. Qingyuan.
How dare you!
Every word I've said is true.
Mrs. Mei arranged everything.
I didn't dare disobey her.
I was just trying to survive, Mrs. Xie!
GOOD.
Very good.
Mei Yinghua,
I want to see how far your greed will go.
Qingyuan,
Get up.
The thing about the estate
It implies a great responsibility.
Because
You took all the blame on yourself
Instead of informing me?
My father
He has maintained an impeccable reputation throughout his life.
I didn't want this scandal
would not tarnish either his good name or yours.
The situation of the estate
It's very complicated.
I am willing to take full responsibility.
First,
I will cut all ties with usurious loans.
After,
I will resolve the outstanding payments to the tenants.
I want to help ease this burden for her.
Give us back our money! Give us back our money!
Silly girl.
This is no small matter.
If you don't handle it well, you could jeopardize your future.
Alright.
La familia Xie
He cannot allow a young woman to bear this responsibility alone.
Let's go back right now.
They should call everyone.
I want to see
What do they intend to do?
And if they still have any respect for me!
La Sra. Xie
he summoned us
with such urgency.
I guess something must have happened.
Yes
You are misinformed.
Don't you know?
Qingyuan has only been there a few days
in charge of the estate
And a very serious problem has already occurred.
When I was in charge,
Nothing like this had ever happened before.
Mrs. Xie has arrived!
What's all the fuss about?
I see that
someone is determined
to not leave me alone.
Today I went to the hacienda and discovered
the scandal of usurious loans granted in secret.
If Qingyuan hadn't reacted in time,
I still wouldn't know that under this roof there was such a wretched maid.
Since everyone is here,
I want to ask you a question.
Granting usurious loans in secret
has tarnished the good name of the Xie family.
According to family rules,
What punishment is appropriate?
Forty blows of the rod.
What insolence!
An old maid dared to commit such a serious offense.
Forty blows with a rod would be too light a punishment.
In my opinion,
After punishing her, they should hand her over to the authorities.
Otherwise, people might believe that he acted on orders from the Xie family.
Nana Rong.
Mrs. Hu.
Everyone is here.
Explain exactly what happened
And don't hide anything.
Sra. Xie.
The practice of secretly granting usurious loans
It's truly outrageous.
I've been there too.
very worried about this matter during the last few days.
Fortunately, I just found a witness.
That's why I decided to bring him here to testify before you.
Which witness?
Bring it.
Soy...
Xue San.
My respects, Mrs. Xie.
Who is this man?
Now they bring before me
to any undesirable person?
Don't be upset, Mrs. Xie.
The matter this man is involved in is extremely serious.
I didn't dare to decide on my own.
That's why I brought it here so you can decide what to do.
Rong.
Rong, save me.
- I'm Saint... - Stop talking nonsense!
Sra. Xie,
I had never seen this man before.
You...
Don't you recognize me?
I am a poor wretch.
After waiting so long, I finally found
to a client who treated me with genuine affection,
But now this misfortune has befallen me.
Rong.
Rong, turn around and look at me!
Rong!
Didn't you say you'd take me with you, Rong?
What nonsense are you talking about!
I have never met a man
as despicable as you.
Nana Rong,
with your monthly salary,
How could you afford to keep a lover?
- Mrs. Xie, that's completely false... - That's right.
At first, I didn't know either.
Until one day
He got drunk
And the truth slipped out.
Then I discovered
all the gold, silver, and jade jewelry he gave me,
as well as the money he paid to buy my freedom,
They came from usurious loans
which he granted in secret
with funds from the treasury.
For years he has used the profits from those loans
to intimidate everyone in Lanxiang.
He also said
who once met a former concubine of this house
and that he even dared to whip her in the middle of the street.
Nana Rong,
How ruthless you are!
You dared to whip my mother in the middle of the street!
Grandmother,
Please do justice for my mother.
My little girl,
Get up.
Sra. Xie,
I'm just a servant.
I don't dare to take on such a serious accusation.
It was Concubine Mei who ordered me
I'll take care of all those predatory loans!
Throughout all these years,
He used that to blackmail me
and force me to do all sorts of dirty things for her.
They?
What dirty things did I order you to do?
You're crazy. You don't know what you're saying anymore.
Nana Rong,
I have treated you well
All these years, right?
Now that you are on the verge of death,
Why are you trying to blame me?
On the verge of death?
Since you say I'm going to die,
I will bring to light
everything you've done!
Don't talk nonsense!
You're a monster!
Wasn't it enough for you to mistreat and humiliate me?
all these years?
San,
Did you hit me?
And you still say they're not lovers?
I'll ask you one last time.
Was it Mrs. Mei who ordered it?
What happened at the ranch?
It was her!
She acted alone.
Mrs. Mei knew nothing.
It was you!
You bribed him
so that he would humiliate me in front of everyone!
I'm going to finish you off!
- You joined the others to beat me up. - Someone come here!
Drag out this miserable servant who betrayed her masters!
Give him forty blows with a stick
and hand her over to the authorities!
Mrs. Xie! Mrs. Xie! I don't want to be taken before the authorities!
Thank you! Thank you!
I am innocent!
Thank you!
Let me go!
Sra. Xie.
- You. - Ms. Xie!
Get out of here.
Don't ever set foot in this house again.
nor disturb their peace.
And you,
Kneel down!
First offense:
not knowing how to choose or supervise your maid
and having tarnished the family name.
Second foul:
having deceived and harmed a young woman in the family,
demonstrating undignified conduct.
Starting today,
the management of the house
It will be left in the hands of the older branch of the family.
Now that you'll be in charge,
I hope you maintain family harmony.
and avoid further disputes.
Yeah.
Mrs. Hu.
[Jingmu Hall]
I was wrong. It was my fault.
Have mercy and spare my life.
As Mrs. Xie instructed me
to take care of this matter,
I asked them to be present.
so they learn their lesson
and take it as a warning.
From now on,
I will not allow anyone to harm the Xie family.
I didn't do it.
They also need to learn
to keep a close eye on those in their charge.
Understood?
- Yes. - Understood.
Sirs,
Please intercede for me.
Nana Liu.
[Jingmu Hall]
Hit her!
I don't want to go!
No...
Mrs. May!
It's time to pay
for all the evil they did.
Thank you, Qingyuan!
Mrs. Hu,
Nanny Rong could not bear the punishment.
Died.
One can escape the evils that heaven sends.
Not those that one causes oneself.
For the good name of the Xie family,
If something like this happens again,
All those involved will be severely punished.
[Residencia Liuhua]
Damn maid!
After keeping it for so many years,
He dared to turn against me just before he died.
Ve
to get him a first-class coffin.
Lest it return as a vengeful spirit to torment me.
Yes, Mrs. May.
Concubine Mei, she certainly knows how to wash her hands.
I truly admire her.
Sr. Yan,
It's very late.
Don't tell me he came looking for me.
Did the foreman leave?
More than one ledger?
Get out of here.
Yeah.
How did it end up in his hands?
the Xie family estate's account book?
How clever.
He recognized him at first sight.
Tell me,
What does he want from me?
Nothing in particular.
I just wanted to tell you
that his beloved son Zhengjun
It knows no limits.
She's so young
And he even dared to steal the grain intended for the victims.
Sr. Yan,
He is overestimating Zhengjun.
He's always been clumsy.
He's not smart enough to do something like that.
It's true, he's not very bright.
But he certainly has plenty of daring.
Would you like me to read to you?
one by one,
all the notes in this book?
It's not necessary.
But don't worry.
This case could become serious or remain minor.
There's still a way to fix it.
It all depends on how much she's willing to offer.
How much do you want?
Not much.
Just five thousand liang.
[Virtue is the true fragrance]
- Everyone, listen to me! - Give us our money back!
[Wealth and prosperity in the home]
Please listen to me first!
Listen to me!
Silence!
[Wealth and prosperity in the home]
Give us our money back! Give us our money back!
Listen to me first!
La Srta. Qingyuan dice
that everyone has worked very hard.
This money is rightfully theirs.
They can rest assured.
As long as Miss Qingyuan is still here,
The estate will not owe them anything.
Very good!
[A bountiful year]
Who would have thought that Ms. Qingyuan would actually pay us what they owed us?
Come on, let's drink!
You have to admit, you do know how to ask.
All at once
You got five thousand silver liang.
Do you have enough to cover the shortfall in the estate?
I checked the accounts thoroughly.
There are even a few hundred liang left over.
So,
A little over four thousand would have been enough.
It's the same.
Consider what's left over as a gesture from me.
Remember that you owe me a favor.
I must admit
that you're getting better every time
deceiving people.
Oh, really?
I said that
That was the cover of the account book of the Xie Estate,
But I never said there was anything written inside.
Because
You're so determined
in cornering the Xie family?
What could he possibly want from the Xie?
I just want to get them out of your heads.
a little more money.
Since we are partners,
Do you still refuse to tell me the truth?
Even though we are partners,
You don't have to
meddling in my affairs.
You already got the estate
and we got rid of Nana Rong.
We both got what we wanted.
Shouldn't we celebrate?
With a drink?
No.
Tonight I must see my grandmother to inform her of an important matter.
Leave.
Have you sorted out the issue with the estate yet?
Yeah.
The accounts have been settled.
of the 131 families who leased the estate.
All the money was refunded.
without exception.
Then,
You will not leave your rooms for three days
and you will copy the sutras a hundred times.
Grandmother...
Did you think no one would notice?
What were you plotting?
There are 131 tenant families
and the sum at stake is enormous.
However capable you may be,
How were you able to solve it?
without help?
Grandmother,
I acknowledge my mistake.
I thought I'd solve it myself,
but...
I didn't expect that
Mr. Yan will be passing by here this morning
and hand over the money without further ado
to settle the accounts of the treasury.
I acted without thinking.
I believed that the Xie family's reputation was the most important thing,
So I made the decision
to use that money to cover the shortfall.
Are you saying that
Did Yan Rui give you five thousand liang of silver?
Yeah.
I acknowledge my mistake.
I see that Mr. Yan and you
They feel something for each other.
What do you think?
What if I arrange your marriage with him?
You would have a good future with him.
Ultimately, women cannot compete with men.
And sooner or later they have to get married and leave home.
That's how it is.
For a woman, being able to marry the man she loves
It is a blessing earned
throughout many lifetimes.
Grandmother.
My mom
She was left destitute far from home and met a tragic end.
I also spent all these years
alone and helpless.
Thanks to the protection of our ancestors,
I was finally able to return to his side
and to know the warmth of a home.
I just want to stay by your side, to take care of you,
Copy the sutras every night and pray for your well-being.
I don't know what wrong I've done.
why would he want to give me away so soon in marriage?
Besides,
I have never met my father.
How could I get married and just leave this house?
Since you mentioned your father,
You must understand that,
while Yan Rui
siga en Hengtang
investigating at will,
will be a threat to the Xie family.
Do you want to
Take advantage of the interest Yan Rui has in me,
I married him
And thus, can we appease him and bring him to our side?
At my age,
I like to see that good stories have a happy ending.
If you two love each other,
Why wouldn't I help them?
to join?
Grandmother.
If it's about the estate
It still makes her distrust me,
I can swear before our ancestors in the ancestral temple.
I am only loyal to the Xie family.
I just want the best for this family.
As for Yan Rui,
I don't feel anything for him.
I only used it
to resolve an emergency.
And...
If I really got married and went to live with the Yan family,
I would spend my days longing to go home
until she became emaciated like a ghost.
Mr. Yan would never come to feel affection for me.
In that case, not even I could
to bring him closer to our family.
Grandmother,
if you still don't trust me
and thinks I'm disloyal,
Judge me by my actions from now on.
I will voluntarily seclude myself
for fifteen days.
I will copy the sutras every day.
and I will pray for you
to demonstrate my loyalty.
Don't say that.
I only wanted the best for you,
But hearing you speak like that,
It seems I didn't act
with due caution.
I just said that.
because I couldn't bear it
to separate from you.
Then get up
And thank your grandmother.
You've been through a lot
with the estate.
I've noticed you look thinner lately.
Nana Liu,
at one point,
Prepare a rice soup with ginseng
and take it to Qingyuan
so that he can regain his strength.
Thank you, mother.
Thank you, Grandma.
Someone come! There's a dead woman!
[Danyue Pavilion]
Jin Chunqing,
You dared to poison her!
What poison?
I don't know anything.
You are about to die
And you still deny it.
Who really killed the concubine Xia?
Why did they kill her to blame my mother?
Thank you, Qingyuan!
I was just following orders.
If you are truly so capable,
Go and confront the powerful people who gave the order.
My mother never got involved in these things.
Why did she end up involved?
We're moving to a place
where it's spring all year round
and there will always be flowers.
As long as I'm with you,
I will be happy anywhere.
It's right here, in the Xie mansion, isn't it?
Chunqing!
Sra. Lian.
You...
What are you up to?
Now that I've found a clue,
I need to try harder.
Very good.
You chose this color very well.
If you're going to embroider cranes,
You should use the overlapping embroidery technique.
Why did you use flat stitches?
You've been practicing for three months.
Look how it turned out!
Mother,
yesterday
I stayed up late copying sutras for my grandmother
and I ended up with sore eyes.
That's why I didn't embroider as usual.
Mira,
Qingrong's embroidery didn't turn out well either.
It doesn't even look like a quail
not even a chick.
Qingru,
They are mandarin ducks.
You always have an answer for everything.
This is the perfect gift for your grandmother's birthday.
You can't take it lightly.
Lady,
The butler Liu wants to see her.
Let's go.
Qinghe,
Your embroidery is beautiful!
Let me see it.
I want to see it too.
It really is beautiful.
The stitches are very well done.
This golden thread
It is very difficult to obtain.
How delicate.
This design is perfect for you.
Qingru.
Look here.
Grandma said
that each one must do her own homework.
You are my older sister.
Isn't it your responsibility to help me?
Besides, you embroider so well
which would be a shame
that no one else could admire him.
Exact.
You embroider so well that
You can make another one.
Devuélvemelo.
It really is very beautiful.
How beautiful.
¡Devuélvemelo!
- And you dare to snatch it from me? - Give it back!
Wow, this is really lively.
How lively the four sisters are!
Grandmother.
Let's see
How did the embroidery turn out?
Even the talking parrot at the Liuhua Residence
It has more life than what you embroidered.
You haven't improved at all.
Grandmother,
Look at my embroidery.
This golden thread
It's very difficult to obtain nowadays.
It's not bad at all.
It's noticeable that
You have made good use of the lessons.
Thank you, Grandma.
Qingru,
What flower did you embroider?
I don't think I've seen it before.
Of course it's a calendula.
How can you
How can someone be so ignorant?
A calendula?
As I recall,
The calendula has elongated petals.
The ones on the outside are a little longer than the ones on the inside.
and are arranged in several layers.
It's a golden camellia.
When it blooms, it has a bell shape.
and usually has a single row of petals.
To faithfully reproduce the natural color of the stamens,
You need to combine pale yellow thread with gold thread.
You have no shame!
Did someone else's frame suddenly grow legs?
And did it end up in your hands?
Grandmother,
We were just playing.
Playing?
Do you think I don't know how they usually
intimidate and trample on others?
Grandmother,
Please calm down.
I only saw that Qinghe embroidered very well.
and I wanted to ask him to teach me.
What will it teach you?
If everyone "learned" like you,
those from the Xie mansion
They would end up abusing others, protected by the power of the family.
Listen to me carefully.
From now on,
if another frame ends up in other people's hands,
whoever is responsible, young or old,
He will spend three days as punishment in the ancestral hall.
There he will learn from our ancestors
what decency and shame mean.
Yeah.
Qingyuan,
Today everything was thanks to you.
Qinghe,
Today you dared to refuse.
That was already a big step.
But
I still don't know how to defend myself.
You did very well.
If you also had a husband
from a powerful family
that would protect you
and that he was the man you love,
Wouldn't that be perfect?
The most prized variety
of the golden camellia
se llama Lanshan.
Qinghe,
You're already halfway there.
Count Kaiguo's wife is very pleased with you
And young Mr. Pei is also in love with you.
You just have to take one more step
And you won't have to fear anyone anymore.
Can I really do it?
Of course.
You can do it.
And if you can't,
I will help you.
Qingyuan,
Both you and Mrs. Jin have always treated me with genuine kindness.
Don't worry.
I will protect you with all my heart,
even if I have to sacrifice everything.
Could you tell me
what happened to my mother
at the time?
If you prefer not to tell me, I'll understand.
It's not that I don't want to tell you.
It's just that
I don't know where to begin.
I was still very young
when Mrs. Jin left.
I only remember that he was kind to everyone.
and very close to my mother.
In his free time
I used to make little toys for myself.
and she was very affectionate with me.
I could never believe it
that had harmed someone.
I am also sure that
My mother would never do something like that.
I beg you, tell me
what really happened that year
and why my mother had to leave the Xie mansion.
I only know that
That year, Mrs. Jin...
Mrs. Xia, what are you doing here?
Does a vulgar actress like you think
Do they deserve to live in the Danyue Pavilion?
It was Mrs. Xie who arranged for me to live here.
Be quiet!
Concubine Xia died that same night.
That made everyone believe
that Mrs. Jin had poisoned her.
But no one could determine
if it was a coincidence
or if there was something hidden behind it all.